

Victor Fernando Lopes de Souza

Engineering Student at CentraleSupélec



8 July 1999, Brazilian



+33 0665923179



victorflosouza@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/victorflosouza



github.com/victorsouza89



1, rue Joliot Curie 91190 Gif-Sur-Yvette, France

About me ——

Passionate for innovation and technology. Interested in approaching complex problems and grasping complex concepts. Enthusiast of Mathematics, Computing, Artificial Intelligence, Machine Learning, System Modeling and Control, Philosophy, Quantum Physics, Financial Markets, Cybersecurity, Blockchain and Discrete Automation.

Skills -

Multiple experiences on Python, LETEX, Matlab, Simulink, Linux, Git, R, Ladder, Java, C++, AutoIt and BASIC.

Experience on Web developing using PHP, HTML, CSS, SQL and JavaScript.

Experience on data analysis and neural nets using Pandas, Numpy, Tensforflow and Keras.

Good Mathematical Background and knowledge in Control's Systems, Automata and Discrete-Event's Systems.

Languages: Portuguese (mother tongue), English, French and Spanish.

Education

2022-2023	Université Paris-Saclay Master in Systems, Signals and Image Processing	Gif-Sur-Yvette (FRA)
2021-2023	CentraleSupélec Engineering, with mention in Control	Gif-Sur-Yvette (FRA)
2018-2023	UFSC - Universidade Federal de Santa Catarina Control and Automation Engineering PAM - Advanced Mathematics Program	Florianópolis (BRA)
2021-2022	Paris IV - Sorbonne Université Bachelor's degree in Philosophy	Paris (FRA)
2014-2017	IFSC - Instituto Federal de Santa Catarina Engineering Technician in Electronics	Florianópolis (BRA)

Work Experience

2020-2021 Student Researcher in Neural Nets

2020 2021	at EMBRAPII, in partnership with Central Energy Worked on building, training, and evaluating LS ing the prediction of precipitation data for energy	STM networks regard-
2018-2021	Student Researcher in Algebraic Topology at IMPA (Brazilian Institute of Pure and Applied Research on advanced topics related to Geome	•
2018–2019	Assistant Professor on Calculus at the Mathematics Department, UFSC Hosted office hours to assist undergraduate str	Florianópolis (BRA) udents
2016–2017	Intern as Web Developer at Oi S.A. (third largest telecommunication com	Florianópolis (BRA) pany in Latin America)

Developed PHP, Shell, BASIC and Kernel scripts to automate tasks

related to the management, monitoring and control of the backbone

Florianópolis (BRA)

Gif-Sur-Yvette (FRA)

Projects

2022

	Implementation of modern control methods for training Neural Nets and use of the Kalman filter as an optimization algorithmx
2022	Exploring portfolio optimization methods, with BNP Gif-Sur-Yvette (FRA) Construction, Implementation and Evaluation of different portfolio allocation methods
2022	System for inform on cancer, with Health Guide AI Gif-Sur-Yvette (FRA) Testing of different recommendation algorithms for this purpose
2021-2022	Neural Nets: Attacks and Robustness, with SystemX Gif-Sur-Yvette (FRA) Study and implementation of some attack methods on NN systems

Training Neural Networks with Kalman Filters

Honours and Awards

2021	BRAFITEC, Merit Scholarship for Double Degree in France
2019	Qualified to Final Phase, OBMU (National University Maths Olympiad)
2018	Freshman Award, OEI (Organization of Ibero-American States)
2017	Silver Medal, OBMEP (National High School Mathematics Olympiad)
2016	Silver Medal, OBMEP (National High School Mathematics Olympiad)
2014	Honourable Mention, OBMEP (National High School Maths Olympiad)